## ALEXANDER DONOVAN-LOWE

Southeast & London, United Kingdom 07443880638 - me@alexdonovanlowe.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Currently employed as the leader of a team of advocates for equality, diversity, and inclusion (EDI) and as part of a small and dynamic EDI team. I am politically savvy, and very personable with excellent communication skills and a yearning to use my knowledge, abilities, and lived experiences to help advance the United Kingdom and our world.

#### **EDUCATION**

in 09/2023

## 09/2022 - Expected Master of Arts: International Relations and Politics *University of Portsmouth* – Portsmouth, United Kingdom

- Aiming to get a First-Class award for this degree.
- Studying five different topic areas:
  - **Exploring International Relations**
  - Contemporary Security in International Relations: Providers and Challenges
  - o Defence and Deterrence
  - Comparative Public Policy and Administration
  - **Researching International Relations**
  - The degree is nurturing my ability to develop a pragmatic understanding of approaches to global and national issues.

09/2018 - 07/2022

### **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science with Honours** University of Portsmouth - Portsmouth, United Kingdom

- Received a Second-Class Upper Division (with Honours) for my degree.
- My final year project centred around developing a practical mechanism to combat the crisis of democracy in the United Kingdom and abroad, and to support protest. As none of this is discussed in my degree curriculum, this experience also massively developed my researching skills.
- Elected to Course Representative for the University of Portsmouth in 2018.
- Member of several societies; IT society, Stand Up to Racism society, and Activists
- A very practical and coursework intensive degree, meaning I am accustomed to working under tight and overlapping deadlines while managing several workloads simultaneously.
- Developed a high competency with technology and software during this degree.
- Had to work independently and co-operatively on several occasions to solve problems, while being sure to adapt and grasp new concepts quickly.

08/2019 - 03/2020

## **Master of Science: Computer Science** Göteborgs Universitet - Göteborg, Sweden

- Received Erasmus Scholarship.
- For my second year of education, I was able to study in Sweden with the European Union's Erasmus scheme.
- It is worth noting that due to the COVID-19 pandemic, I could not complete this placement, but I still received 20 credits in recognition of studying done.
- This experience really broadened my perspectives and made me much more interested in international news, events, and inequalities.

#### **Work history**

10/2021 - Current

#### **Lead PGM Ambassador**

#### University of Portsmouth Student's Union – Portsmouth, Hampshire

- Worked with several teams across the university and the union to write new policy and practice guidelines for a vast range of topics.
- Wrote communications for senior members of staff to detail projects that the team and I worked on.
- Co-ordinated a social media presence to inform the students and the public of our
- Maintained a constant and up to date knowledge base of social justice and issues of

- equality across the globe, and in the United Kingdom, to ensure effectiveness in our mission.
- Worked with external organisers to further racial equity within the local community and society that the university exists in.
- Lobbying the university itself to implement a Zero-Tolerance to Racism policy, while also doing micro-implementation to get as much of that policy put into practice.
- Worked alongside staff within the university and the student's union to implement policy changes that will close the awarding gap of local minority students.
- Co-ordinated several teams to try and tackle the awarding gap and racial inequity at the university from a faculty level as a more bottom-up approach.
- Attended several "panels" where matters of equality and diversity were discussed, as an opportunity to propagate changes that the student and staff body wanted to see.
- Ensure that my team were engaged, motivated, and mentally healthy. This involved arranging psychological support for those who needed it, due to discussing their racial trauma and the impact of micro-aggressions.
- Liaised with senior management and student representatives to gather data and research to use as evidence for policy and regulation changes.

08/2022 – Current

# Equality, Diversity, Inclusion & Engagement Team Support University of Portsmouth – Portsmouth, Hampshire

- Great experience to engage in Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion (EDI) matters within a Higher Education setting.
- Updated the University's Gender Expression & Identity Policy to better guarantee it functions aptly for our transgender staff and students. As part of this, I had to liaise with several teams to ensure the process of name and gender changes in our system are both up-to-date and as confidential as possible. This also means we abide legislation like the Equality Act 2010 and the Gender Recognition Act 2004.
- Contributed to the University's Athena Swan submission by helping to co-ordinate and engage the Athena Swan Champion's across the university, also providing them with materials that they may find useful to better reach gender equity across the University.
- Assisted the EDI team in their work on the Race Equality Charter (REC), by highlighting potential pitfalls in communication channels and promoting the student voice within our REC.
- Critically reviewed all training courses provided at the University to ensure compliance to legislation, as well as, to improve how much the training sticks with staff and that it promotes EDI.

#### ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS - CERTIFICATE PROOF AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

Confronting Bias: Thriving Across Our Differences
National Association of State Boards of Accountancy (NASBA) – Continuing
Professional Education (CPE) Credit - 1.60

Driving Change and Anti-Racism Project Management Institute

Inclusive Leadership
Project Management Institute

#### REFERENCES – CONTACT DETAILS AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

Laurie Jones – Line Manager University of Portsmouth Student's Union – Portsmouth, Hampshire

Nadim Bakhshov – Personal Tutor and Project Supervisor University of Portsmouth – Portsmouth, Hampshire

**Yvonne Howard** – Line Manager and Director of Race and Equality **University of Portsmouth** – Portsmouth, Hampshire